A Guide to the Republican Committee of Fairfax County Papers, 1965-1978
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Republican Committee of Fairfax County Papers, 1965-1978
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 05-04
3.5 linear feet
The Republican Committee of Fairfax County Papers consist of 3.5 linear feet and spans the years 1965-1978 and contains newspaper clippings, pamphlets, correspondence, press releases, registered voter lists, and other documents related to the Fairfax County Republican Party, Fairfax County elections (including materials on Republican and Democratic candidates), and Fairfax County political issues from that time period. Issues addressed include busing, pollution, education, and the economy.
Republican Committee of Fairfax County
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Unknown
Historical and Biographical Information
The Republican Committee of Fairfax County is responsible for conducting business in Fairfax County for the Republican Party. This includes calling county conventions and other mass meetings, nominating candidates for public office, and clarifying official positions of the Fairfax County Republican Party. Although the Republican Party was founded, on a national level, before the Civil War, the Party was not very active in Virginia until well after the war. The Fairfax County Republican Committee’s origins appear to date back to at least the 1880s.
Scope and Content
The Republican Committee of Fairfax County Papers consist of 3.5 linear feet and spans the years 1965-1978 and contains newspaper clippings, pamphlets, correspondence, press releases, registered voter lists, and other documents related to the Fairfax County Republican Party, Fairfax County elections (including materials on Republican and Democratic candidates), and Fairfax County political issues from that time period. Issues addressed include busing, pollution, education, and the economy. Republican Party documents include newsletters (“Fairfax County Republican Newsletter”), instructions to precinct captains and electoral workers, and Fairfax precinct voter listings. The bulk of the material is composed of newspaper clippings. Many of these were affixed to generic Republican letterhead but are now coming loose and are extremely fragile.
The collection formerly had no original order to it. Original folder titles have been retained and arranged alphabetically by topic and then alphabetically by politician. The researcher is advised that there is a large amount of overlap in related topics. When looking for materials on a particular political figure, the researcher should not only look at folders devoted to that person, but also folders on any people that person might have run against and folders that cover the time period when that person was politically active.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Republican Committee of Fairfax County
Container List
- Burling Park, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Convention Delegates, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Crime, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Drugs, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Economy, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Election, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Election, Chair-Board of Supervisors, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Fact Sheets for Election Day Judges, Clerks, and Poll Watchers, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Fairfax County Election, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Fairfax County Election, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Fairfax County Issues, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Fairfax County - Providence District, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Fairfax County - Springfield District, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Fairfax County Republican Candidates Newsletter, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Fairfax County Republican Convention, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Fairfax County Republican Newsletter, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Forward Fairfax Precinct Listings, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Health and Welfare, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Republican Party - Miscellaneous (Folder 1 of 2), 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Republican Party - Miscellaneous (Folder 2 of 2), 1969-1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Roads and Highways, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- School Problems/Busing, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Schools and Education (Folder 1 of 2), 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Heffalump Society, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Highways - Transit - Metro, 1970-1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Housing, 1968-1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous Political Clippings, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Pari-Mutuel/Gambling, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Politics - Democratic Party - Miscellaneous, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Pollution, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Redistricting, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Schools and Education (Folder 2 of 2), 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Scrapbook: 1. Freedom Memorial in Arlington 2. Federal Pollution Control Program 3. Miscellaneous Joel T. Broyhill Clippings, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Sewer, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- State Problems and Legislative Activities, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Utilities, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Joseph Alexander - Lee District, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Byron F. Andrews, Jr., 1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- R. Barry Ashby, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Warren E. Barry, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Walter S. Boone, Chair-Fairfax County Board of Supervisors, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Walter S. Boone, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Harriet F. Bradley - Dranesville District, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Adelard L. Brault - Democrat, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Joel T. Broyhill, 1970-1973 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- James Burch, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Harry F. Byrd, Jr., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Vincent F. Callahan, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Warren Davis, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- James H. Dillard, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Robert R. Dively, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- William Durland, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Wyatt Durrette, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Clive L. Duval - Democrat, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Robert C. Fitzgerald (Dem) - Lt. Gov., 1971 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Ray L. Garland, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Ray Garland for Senate [contains photograph], 1970 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Joseph V. Gartlan - Democrat, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Mills Godwin, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Victor C. Gray, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Carol Griffee, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Herbert E. Harris, II, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Robert E. Harris, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Stephen Hartwell, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Horace Henderson, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Donald B. Henretty - Dem., 1971 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- John F. Herrity, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Linwood Holton Gubernatorial Campaign, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Linwood Holton, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- William S. Hoofnagle, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Robert F. Horan, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- George J. Kostel, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Alan H. Magazine, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Charles Majer, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Virginia McEnearney, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Harold O. Miller, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Myron J. Mintz, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Audrey Moore, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- William H. Moss, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Richard Obenshain, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Jean Packard, Undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Stanford E. Parris, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Martha Pennino, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Rufus Phillips, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Clifford H. Pruefer, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- George C. Rawlings, Jr., 1970 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Shirley Rigg, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Shirley Rigg, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Richard J. Ryder, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- James Scott, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- William L. Scott, 1970-1972 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- George P. Shafran, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- William B. Spong, Jr., 1970-1972 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Darrell Stearns, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- David A. Sutherland, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- James Swinson, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- James Tate, 1972-1976 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Raymond V. Walsh, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- John M. Wilkins, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Thomas B. Wright, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Thomas B. Wright, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 19)